Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 7A: Photographs, 1902-1971; 10.5 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes and 6 oversized flat boxes.
  - World War I -- Remarque, circa 1914-1918 (Box 98, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - World War I -- Remarque, unknown person in the baracks, 1918 (Box 98, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - World War I -- Remarque with dog, circa 1914-1918 (Box 98, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - World War I -- Remarque, circa 1914-1918 (Box 98, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - World War I -- Remarque, three unknown people, 1918 (Box 98, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Peter Remark with dog, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Peter Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Peter Remark, unknown person, 1948 (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Peter Remark, 1950 (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Peter Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Peter Remark and horse, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - Peter Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 7)
  - Peter Remark, unknown person, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 8)
  - Peter Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 3, Item 9)
  - Erna Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Elfriede Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - Peter Remark, Erna Remark, undated (Box 98, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Peter Remark, Erna Remark reading Arc de Triomphe, circa 1945 (Box 98, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Peter Remark, Erna Remark reading Arc de Triomphe, circa 1945 (Box 98, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Remarque, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 1-15)
  - Remarque on a boat, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 16)
  - Remarque in a car, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 17)
  - Remarque, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 18-19)
  - Remarque at the sea, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 20)
  - Remarque, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 21)
  - Group photo, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 22)
  - Remarque, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 23-34)
  - Group photo, 1919 (Box 98, Folder 6, Item 35)
  - Remarque, 1920s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 1-4)
  - Remarque, after 1929 (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 5-7)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 8-12)
  - Remarque in bed, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 13)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 14-22)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 23)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 24-26)
  - Remarque, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 27-29)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 30-31)
  - Remarque, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 32-33)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 34-44)
  - Remarque, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 45-46)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 47-54)
  - Remarque in front of a house in Switzerland, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 55)
  - Remarque, 1940s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 56-62)
  - Remarque, 1930s-1940s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 63-67)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 68-69)
  - Remarque, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 70)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, 1930s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 71)
  - Remarque in study, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 72-73)
  - Remarque on a boat (Lake Maggiore), undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 74)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 75-76)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, 1940s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 77-84)
  - Remarque, 1940s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 85-88)
  - Remarque speaking with an unknown person, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 89)
  - Remarque in study, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 90)
  - Remarque in the street, 1940s (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 91-95)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 96-98)
  - Remarque in a house in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 7, Item 99-101)
  - Remarque in study, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Remarque in a cafe, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 2)
  - Remarque, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 3)
  - Remarque and LPs, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 4)
  - Remarque in study, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 5-7)
  - Remarque in Bad Rothenfelde, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 8)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 9-16)
  - Remarque in Bad Rothenfelde, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 17-18)
  - Remarque on Lake Maggiore, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 19-28)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 29-50)
  - Remarque in front of Lancia, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 51)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 52-76)
  - Remarque and Globus, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 77-79)
  - Remarque, 1963 (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 80)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 80-94)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 95-97)
  - Remarque and wine in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 98-105)
  - Remarque and wine, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 105)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 106-107)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 108-109)
  - Remarque in Venice, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 110-114)
  - Remarque in study, undated (Box 98, Folder 8, Item 115-120)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 121-126)
  - Remarque in front of a lake in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 127-132)
  - Remarque in a house in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 133-142)
  - Remarque with a sculpture, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 143)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 144-147)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 148)
  - Remarque, 1966 (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 149)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 150)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 151-153)
  - Remarque, 1967 (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 154)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 155-157)
  - Remarque in Porto Ronco, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 158-159)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 160-162)
  - Remarque, 1968 (Box 99, Folder 8, Item 163-164)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1960s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 1-22)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1950s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 23-24)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1960s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 25-26)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1950s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 27)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1930s-1940s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 28-30)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1920s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 31)
  - Remarque passport photos, 1930s-1940s (Box 99, Folder 9, Item 32-33)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 1-3)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House/Lake, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 4-9)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Lake, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 10-13)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 14-17)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 18-25)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Construction work on house, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 26-27)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Ship on the lake, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 28)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Lakeside, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 29-33)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, lake, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 34-39)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 40-43)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Lakeside, boat, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 44-48)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 49)
  - Tivoli, Villa d'Este, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 50)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 51-75)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 76)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Lake, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 77)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Lake, boat, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 78-79)
  - Ronco/Lake Maggiore, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 80-86)
  - Ronco, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 88-90)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 91)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, lake, 1930s (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 93-94)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Garden, lake, house, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 95-99)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Terrace, lake, 1963 (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 100-104)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 105)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Terrace, lake, 1963 (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 106)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- House, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 107)
  - Porto Ronco/Lake Maggiore -- Terrace, candlestick, undated (Box 99, Folder 10, Item 108)
  - Honorary citizenship of Ascona Award -- Remarque, Paulette Goddard, unknown people, 1968 (Box 99, Folder 11, Item 1-38)
  - Remarque and Ilse Jutta Zambona, undated (Box 99, Folder 12, Item 1-12)
  - Ilse Jutta Zambona -- Portraits, 1920s-1958 (Box 99, Folder 13, Item 1-99)
  - Ilse Jutta Zambona -- Portraits, undated (Box 99, Folder 14, Item 1-21)
  - Natasha Paley Wilson -- Portraits, undated (Box 99, Folder 15, Item 1-8)
  - Remarque and Marlene Dietrich, undated (Box 99, Folder 16, Item 1-2)
  - Marlene Dietrich -- Personal Portraits, undated (Box 100, Folder 17, Item 1-8)
  - Marlene Dietrich -- Promotional Stills, 1930s (Box 100, Folder 18, Item 1-36)
  - Marlene Dietrich -- Portraits, undated (Box 127, Folder 19, Item 1-50)
  - Unidentified men, undated (Box 100, Folder 21, Item 1-5)
  - Unidentified groups, 1930s-1960s (Box 100, Folder 22, Item 1-24)
  - Houses -- Berlin, Wannsee, Los Angeles, Osnabruck, undated (Box 100, Folder 23, Item 1-10)
  - Remarque -- Promotional, 1957 (Box 100, Folder 24, Item 1-3)
  - Remarque -- Promotional for Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die, 1950s (Box 100, Folder 25, Item 1-5)
  - Inauguration plaque, Berlin, 1971 (Box 100, Folder 26, Item 1-3)
  - Photo Album -- Lake Maggiore, 1936 (Box 100, Folder 27, Item 1)
  - Osnabrück -- Materials for Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk, 1945 (Box 100, Folder 28, Item 1-19)
  - Eva Braun and the Führerbunker -- Materials for Der letzte Akt / The Last Ten Days, undated (Box 100, Folder 29, Item 1-5)
  - Paestum, undated (Box 100, Folder 30, Item 1-7)
  - Pompeii, undated (Box 100, Folder 30, Item 8-11)
  - Paestum, undated (Box 100, Folder 30, Item 12-16)
  - Tivoli, undated (Box 100, Folder 30, Item 17)
  - Paestum, undated (Box 100, Folder 30, Item 18-23)
  - Battle of Verdun, 1920s (Box 100, Folder 31, Item 1-2)
  - Hannover, Berlin, after 1945 (Box 100, Folder 32, Item 1-13)
  - Autograph cards, undated (Box 100, Folder 33, Item 1-16)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 100, Folder 34, Item 1-10)
  - Negatives, 1920s-1930s (Box 100, Folder 35, Item 1-16)
  - Photo Album -- Porto Ronco, 1948 (Box 135, Folder 36, Item 1)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- stills, 1930 (Box 101, Folder 37, Item 1-6)
  - Die letzte Station -- stills, 1961 (Box 101, Folder 38, Item 1-12)
  - Arc de Triomphe / Arch of Triumph -- stills, undated (Box 101, Folder 39, Item 1)
  - The other love -- stills, undated (Box 101, Folder 40, Item 1)
  - Remarque, Carmen Amayo, Daro Amajo, Leonore Amayo, J. Iglesias, Antonio Amayo, Jose Amayo, Franzisco Ramirez, undated (Box 101, Folder 50, Item 1)
  - Remarque, 1958 (Box 101, Folder 50, Item 2)
  - Remarque, Isaac Stern, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 50, Item 3)
  - Remarque, Jack L. Warner, Mervyn Le Roy, undated (Box 101, Folder 50, Item 4)
  - Unknown woman, undated (Box 101, Folder 51, Item 1)
  - Gypsy Olla, undated (Box 101, Folder 52, Item 1)
  - Remarque, Gypsy Markoff, undated (Box 101, Folder 53, Item 1-2)
  - Toni Hollingsworth -- Portraits, undated (Box 101, Folder 54, Item 1-4)
  - Elsie Mende -- Portraits, 1941-1945 (Box 101, Folder 55, Item 1-2)
  - Penny Pieslany -- Portraits, 1937 (Box 101, Folder 56, Item 1-11)
  - Remarque, Penny Pieslany -- Portraits, undated (Box 101, Folder 57, Item 1-4)
  - Unknown women, undated (Box 101, Folder 58, Item 1-13)
  - Unknown women, undated (Box 101, Folder 59, Item 1-8)
  - Remarque with unidentified women, undated (Box 102, Folder 60, Item 1-26)
  - Remarque in groups, undated (Box 102, Folder 61, Item 1-99)
  - Remarque and Paulette Goddard in Groups, undated (Box 102, Folder 62, Item 1-38)
  - Cats, undated (Box 102, Folder 63, Item 1-7)
  - Goats, undated (Box 102, Folder 63, Item 8)
  - Ape, undated (Box 102, Folder 63, Item 9)
  - Remarque and Paulette Goddard with car with Ticino license plate, undated (Box 102, Folder 64, Item 1-3)
  - Remarque with cars with German license plates, 1927-1928 (Box 102, Folder 64, Item 4-26)
  - Remarque with cars with Swiss license plates, undated (Box 102, Folder 64, Item 27-29)
  - Remarque with car with Ticino license plate, undated (Box 102, Folder 64, Item 30-31)
  - Remarque and car, undated (Box 102, Folder 64, Item 32)
  - Remarque and Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 102, Folder 65, Item 1-45)
  - Porto Ronco -- Construction activities and landslide aftermath, 1965 (Box 102, Folder 66, Item 1-17)
  - Der Funke Leben / Spark of Life -- Dutch book window, undated (Box 102, Folder 67, Item 1)
  - Dogs, undated (Box 102, Folder 68, Item 1-56)
  - Dogs, undated (Box 102, Folder 69, Item 1-43)
  - Funerals of Jean Sclumberger and Peter Remark, 1954 (Box 102, Folder 70, Item 1-20)
  - Remarque Gravestone, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 71, Item 1-10)
  - Portraits of women, undated (Box 102, Folder 72, Item 1-34)
  - Jutta Ilse Zambona, undated (Box 102, Folder 72, Item 35)
  - Portraits of women, undated (Box 102, Folder 72, Item 36-45)
  - Jutta Ilse Zambona, undated (Box 102, Folder 72, Item 46-47)
  - Portraits of women, undated (Box 102, Folder 72, Item 48-53)
  - Remarque, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 1)
  - Unidentified group, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 2)
  - Remarque and group, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 3-5)
  - Remarque, Allica Bauer, Tay-tay, Peter Bauer, Hans A. Bauer, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 6)
  - Davos, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 7)
  - Trudel Schmidt, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 8)
  - Unknown woman, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 9)
  - Osnabrück, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 10-12)
  - Jakob Wassermann, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 13)
  - Fritz Hörstemeier, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 14-15)
  - Unidentified group, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 16)
  - Willi Niemeyer, Soa Niemeyer, Anjo Niemeyer, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 17)
  - Dr. Gerd Doeny, 1968 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 18)
  - Georg Middendorf, Georg Beil, Franz Tobergte, Hermann Boitmann, Hans Domin, Bernhard Tobergte, Karl Fleddermann, Friedel Hünecke, 1962 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 19)
  - Nelly Vappsenheim, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 20)
  - Unidentified people, 1950 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 21)
  - Heinz Thiel, Schimm, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 22)
  - Two men, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 23)
  - Carl Zuckmayer, 1967 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 24)
  - Man and woman, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 25)
  - Ch. Baumann, 1938 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 26)
  - Sam Salz, 1959 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 27)
  - Men, undated (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 28)
  - Anny, 1936 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 29)
  - Remarque, 1963 (Box 102, Folder 73, Item 30-31)
  - Erotic Photos, undated (Box 102, Folder 74, Item 1)
  - Framed portraits of Remarque and Casa Monte Tabor, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 143)
  - Framed portraits of Remarque and others, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 144)
  - Framed photographs of Remarque, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 145)
  - Framed photograph of Remarque and dog, undated (Box 146)
- Series 7B: Portraits, 1917-1929; 3.25 Linear Feet in 2 oversized flat boxes.
  This series contains hand drawn portraits of Remarque.
  - Drawing of Remarque by Emil Stumpp, 1929 (Box 134, Folder 1-4)
  - Chalk portrait of Remarque as a Soldier, 1917 (Box 136, Folder 5)
- Series 8A: Printed Materials about Remarque (Clippings), 1929-1979; 6 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 3 oversized flat boxes.
  This series contains clippings with reviews of Remarque's works; biographical profiles of Remarque; bestseller lists; Remarque's marriage to Paulette Goddard; film and theater reviews; advertisements; Hollywood gossip columns; interviews; and other articles related to Remarque.
  Arranged by subject alphabetially.
  - Clippings -- 65th Birthday, 1963 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - Clippings -- 70th Birthday, 1968 (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - Clippings -- Arc de Triomphe / Arch of Triumph, circa 1945-1950 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - Clippings -- Biographical, undated (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Clippings -- Biographical, 1930s-1940s (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - Clippings -- Biographical, 1950s (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- Biographical, 1960-1964 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - Clippings -- Biographical, 1965-1969 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - Clippings -- Biographical, 1970s (Box 132, Folder 8)
  - Clippings -- Films Worked on by Remarque, 1930-1958 (Box 132, Folder 11)
  - Clippings -- Der Funke Leben / Spark of Life, 1946-1953 (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- Der Himmel kennt keine Günstlinge / Heaven Has No Favorites, 1961-1962 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Clippings -- Der letzte Akt / The Last Ten Days, circa 1955 (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Clippings -- Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk, circa 1956 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- Der Weg zurück / The Road Back, 1931-1937 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Clippings -- Die Nacht von Lissabon / The Night in Lisbon, 1962-1971 (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Clippings -- Die Traumbude / The Dream Room, 1920 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Clippings -- Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades, circa 1936-1955 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Clippings -- Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades, circa 1936-1955 (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Clippings -- Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades, circa 1936-1955 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Clippings -- Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front, circa 1930-1968 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- Liebe Deinen Nächsten / Flotsam, 1941-1962 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Clippings -- Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise, 1971-1972 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Clippings -- Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die, 1954-1960 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and Poster -- Full Circle / Die letzte Station, 1956-1967 (Box 132, Folder 10)
  - Interviews, 1960s (Box 132, Folder 9)
- Series 8B: Printed Materials about Remarque (Full Copies), 1929-1972; 9 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 5 oversized flat boxes.
  This series contains full copies of newspapers and magazines with reviews of Remarque's works; biographical profiles of Remarque; bestseller lists; Remarque's marriage to Paulette Goddard; film and theater reviews; advertisements; Hollywood gossip columns; interviews; and other articles related to Remarque.
  - Michael Burrows,"The films of Erich Maria Remarque", 1972 (Box 134, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - "Life and Letters: Correspondence between Erich Remarque and General Sir Ian Hamilton," edited by Desmond MacCarthy, 1929 (Box 134, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - Achim Anders. "Seid auf der Hut. Zum Tode von Erich Maria Remarque", 1971 (Box 134, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- theater program, 1960 (Box 134, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - "Symphonie Macabre" by Robert Breuer, 1946 (Box 134, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - "Remarque und die gefallenen Studenten" by Walther Kowalski, 1931 (Box 134, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - "Hier lebt und wirkt Erich Maria Remarque" in Ringiers Blatt für Alle mit Frauen und Mode Zeitung, 1960 (Box 135, Folder 2, Item 1-2)
  - "Erich Maria Remarque" in the Philadelphia Inquirer, 1946 (Box 135, Folder 2, Item 3-4)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die -- related article, 1954 (Box 135, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- related article, 1944 (Box 135, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Burhan Arpad, "Gri mavi gözlerinde isil dostluk vardi. Elimi uzatti:'Türkiye'ye gelecegim. Hem belki de önümüzdeki yil..'", 1956 (Box 135, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Obituaries of Remarque, 1970 (Box 135, Folder 3, Item 2-4)
  - Villa ohne Nummer und Namensschild. Wir besuchten ein berühmtes Ehepaar: Erich Maria Remarque und Paulette Goddard. Prominenz im Tessin" in Freien Stunden (Zürich), 1965 (Box 135, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Burhan Arpad, "Remarque Üzerine", 1957 (Box 135, Folder 4, Item 2)
  - Der Funke Leben / Spark of Life -- related article, 1952 (Box 135, Folder 4, Item 3)
  - Hans Habe, "14-Tage-Buch.", 1938 (Box 135, Folder 4, Item 4)
  - Hans Habe, "Mein Nachbar Remarque. Zu seinem 65.Geburtstag.", 1963 (Box 135, Folder 4, Item 5)
  - Liebe Deinen Nächsten / Flotsam -- related articles, 1941 (Box 135, Folder 4, Item 6)
  - Full Circle / Die letzte Station -- programs, 1956-1965 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 1-2)
  - Schatten im Paradies / Shadows in Paradise -- related article, 1972 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 3)
  - Remarque at 70 -- clippings, 1968 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 4-5)
  - "Aus der Welt des Gildenbuches und seiner Autoren" in Büchergilde Gutenberg (Zürich), 1958 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 6)
  - Remarque at 60 article, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 7-8)
  - Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk, 1956 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 9)
  - Remarque at 70 -- clippings, 1968 (Box 133, Folder 5, Item 10-11)
  - "Der neue Remarque im Streit der Meinungen", 1931 (Box 135, Folder 6, Item 1-2)
  - "Beachtenswerte Rezensionen", undated (Box 135, Folder 6, Item 3)
  - "Werke von Erich Maria Remarque" at Verlag Kurt Desch, 1957 (Box 135, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die -- related article, 1954 (Box 135, Folder 7, Item 2)
  - Full Circle / Die letzte Station -- reviews, 1956 (Box 135, Folder 7, Item 3-4)
  - Remarque at 60 article, 1958 (Box 135, Folder 7, Item 5)
  - "Remarque: Weltbürger wider Willen" in Spiegel (Hamburg), 1952 (Box 135, Folder 7, Item 6)
  - Gerhard Ponemunski -- Deutsch II, undated (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 1)
  - Full Circle / Die letzte Station -- programs, 1964-1965 (Box 126, Folder 9, Item 2)
  - Arc de Triomphe / Arch of Triumph -- related clippings, 1947 (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 3)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- related clippings, 1931 (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 4)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die, 1954 (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 5-7)
  - Verlag Kiepenheuer & Witsch Erich Maria Remarque brochure, undated (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 8)
  - Letter from Remarque in Rothenburg und die Tauber, 1963 (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 9)
  - "Auszeichnungenunserer Mitglieder" in Der Literat: Zeitschrift für Literatur und Kunst (Frankfurt), 1969 (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 10)
  - Remarque at 65 -- related clippings, 1963 (Box 138, Folder 9, Item 11)
  - Remarque at 70 -- clippings, 1968 (Box 131, Folder 10, Item 1)
  - Zeit zu leben und Zeit zu sterben / A Time to Love and a Time to Die, 1954 (Box 131, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - Der Funke Leben / Spark of Life -- clipping, 1952 (Box 131, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - "Erich Maria Remarque. Ein Interview von Prinz Konstantin von Bayern" in Das Schönste. Die Monatsschrift für alle Freunde der schönen Künste (München), 1956 (Box 131, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - Der schwarze Obelisk / The Black Obelisk, 1957 (Box 131, Folder 10, Item 5-6)
  - Helmut Jahn, "Ein Leben ohne Frauen ist kein Leben", 1963 (Box 131, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Anneliese Friedmann, "Begegnung miteinem Mann von Welt", 1968 (Box 135, Folder 11, Item 3)